A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Issue Books, Series 17 FA363
Rockefeller Archive Center
- First Gubernatorial Term, 1958-1962; 2; 5.4 Cubic Feet
  - Volume 15 - General Background, 1958-1962 (Box 29, Folder 161)
    Pre-Campaign materials prepared by Republican Research Unit (William Embler, June Martin,) Note: The items listed below are general; the materials covering specific topics are in the topic books.
    Tab 11 Nelson A. Rockefeller Summary Positions 1958 Campaign -- New York Republican State Committee, n.d., issued late October 1958.
    Tab 12 Summary of the Differences in Major Issues between Republicans in New York State and Governor Harriman -- October 27, 1958.
    Tab 13 Memorandum: Campaign Promises and Their Implementation -- W. J. Ronan to NAR, November 20, 1950.
    Tab 14 NAR Statement -- Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 7, 1959.
    Tab 15 NAR Statement -- Annual Budget Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, February 2, 1959.
    Tab 16 NAR Statement -- Administration Program and Other Major Legislation passed during 1959 session.
    Tab 17 NAR Statement -- Address on Administration accomplishments, Annual Dinner, New York Republican State Committee, June 4, 1959.
  - Volume 15 - General Background, 1958-1962 (Box 29, Folder 162)
    Tab 18 Summary of "Rockefeller Studies" -- Legislative Research Report, November 11, 1959.
    Tab 19 NAR Statement -- Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 6, 1960.
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- Annual Budget Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, February 1, 1960.
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- on 1960 Legislative Accomplishments, April 1, 1960.
    Tab 22 NAR Statement -- outlining 1960 Legislative Accomplishments, April 20, 1960.
    Tab 23-38 Missing
  - Volume 15 - General Background, 1958-1962 (Box 29, Folder 163)
    Tab 39 NAR Statement -- Annual Budget Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 31, 1962.
    Tab 40 NAR Statement -- on Major Accomplishments of the 1962 Legislative Session, March 31, 1962.
    Tab 41 NAR Statement -- Address at Tenth Annual Republican Women's Conference on role of Republican party on the national scene, and reviewing Republican 4 years of accomplishments in New York, Washington, D.C., April 17, 1962.
  - Volume 15 - General Background, 1958-1962 (Box 29, Folder 164)
    Tab 42 Summary of 1962 Legislation -- Legislative Research Report, May 4, 1962.
    Tab 43 "The Rockefeller Record" -- Four Years of Dynamic Achievement, New York State Republican Committee, June 14, 1962.
    Tab 44 The Four Year Record of Republican Accomplishments -- Legislative Research Report.
  - Volume 16 - Health, Mental Health, and Narcotics Addiction, 1958-1962 (Box 29, Folder 165)
    Tab 1 Summary and Background on Health, Mental Health, and Health Insurance in New York State -- prepared for NAR Special New York Project (Perkins-Kieffer), July 2, 1958.
    Tab 2 Fact Sheet -- "Health" prepared by Republican Legislative Research Staff, 1958.
    Tab 3 NAR Campaign Statement -- NAR remarks at Beth Israel Hospital, September 23, 1958.
    Tab 4 NAR Campaign Statement -- Policy Statement on Labor, October 3, 1958.
    Tab 5 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from remarks at dinner of Schenectady County Republican Committee, October 13, 1958.
    Tab 6 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from remarks at dinner of Essex, Rensselaer, Saratoga, Warren, and Washington County Republican Committees, October 15, 1958.
    Tab 7 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from NAR Campaign Statement, October 19, 1958.
    Tab 9 Press Release, April 15, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 2917, Pr. 4890, relaxing certification requirements for x-ray operators, April 13, 1959.
    Tab 10 Press Release, April 21, 1959 -- Veto Memorandum on Senate Int. 2789, Pr. 2921, eliminating mandatory minimum penalties for sale or possession of narcotics, April 20, 1959.
    Tab 11 Press Release, April 23, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 1444, Pr. 4290, extending health insurance coverage for optometric services, April 22, 1959.
    Tab 12 Press Release, April 25, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 3547, Pr. 3821, authorizing treatment to additional youthful drug addicts, April 24, 1959.
    Tab 13 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Chapters 460, 394, 792, 324, 1959-1960 Executive Budget.
    Tab 14 NAR Statement -- appointing Committee to analyze hospital facilities and medical care programs in New York, July 31, 1959.
    Tab 15 NAR Statement -- appointing Special Task Force and Advisory Committee on Catastrophic Expense Health Insurance, September 3, 1959.
    Tab 16 NAR Statement -- Address to American Public Health Association, Inc., on reviews of major health problems, New Jersey, October 11, 1959.
    Tab 17 NAR Statement -- Address to Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies on Special Task Force on Narcotics Addiction, New York City, November 5, 1959.
    Tab 18 Summary of Special Studies on M'Naghten Rule, Catastrophic Health Insurance, Hospital Care and Drug Addiction -- Legislative Research Report, November 11, 1959.
    Tab 19 NAR Statement -- Address at Little White House Conference on Aging, New York City, December 1, 1959.
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- on conversion of Mt. McGregor Veterans Rest Camp into Annex, Rome State School for Mentally Retarded Children, December 16, 1959.
  - Volume 16 - Health, Mental Health, and Narcotics Addiction, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 166)
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 6, 1960.
    Tab 22 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address to New York State Women's Joint Legislative Forum, January 12, 1960.
    Tab 23 NAR Statement -- on new school for retarded in Suffolk County, January 26, 1960.
    Tab 24 NAR Statement -- announcement on special treatment for parolee-addicts, January 28, 1960.
    Tab 25 Report -- Interim Report of Governor's Cabinet Committee on Hospital and Medical Care, February 29, 1960.
    Tab 26 NAR Statement -- Special Message to the Legislature on Mental Health and Public Health (includes Narcotics Addiction), March 7, 1960.
    Tab 27 Transcript -- Statewide telecast by Governor Rockefeller and Commissioner of Mental Hygiene, on Mental Health, March 8, 1960.
    Tab 28 NAR Statement -- joint Statement by Governor Rockefeller and Legislative Leaders on conversion of group health insurance for senior citizens, March 24, 1960.
    Tab 29 NAR Statement -- Special Message to the Legislature on health insurance for senior citizens, March 28, 1960.
    Tab 30 Press Release, April 4, 1960 -- Executive Order establishing Interdepartmental Health and Hospital Council, March 31, 1960.
    Tab 31 Press Release, April 18, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 3751, Pr. 3899, imposing strict penalties on drug addicts, April 14, 1960.
    Tab 32 Press Release, April 30, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 4541, Pr. 5320, on creation of Mental Health Research Council, April 29, 1960.
    Tab 33 Press Release, May 1, 1960 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 3837, Pr. 4010, authorizing podiatrists to administer narcotic drugs, April 30, 1960.
    Tab 34 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters 311, 918, 141, 823, 819, 920, 98, 144, 1028, 869, 418, 854, 1960-1961 Executive Budget, Chapters 529, 530.
    Tab 35 NAR Statement -- excerpt from transcript of press conference on new health insurance program, May 4, 1960.
    Tab 36 NAR Statement -- statement by Commissioner Hoch and NAR Statement before President's Interdepartmental Committee on Narcotics, New York City, May 18, 1960.
    Tab 37 NAR Statement -- Address at New York State Public Health Conference on "Better Health," New York City, May 24, 1960.
    Tab 38 NAR Statement -- Address at dedication of new Basic Science building, on battle against cancer, Buffalo, June 17, 1960.
    Tab 39 NAR Statement -- Program presented by NAR at Annual Governors' Conference on Health Care for the Aged, June 29, 1960.
    Tab 40 NAR Statement -- excerpt from statement to Republican National Platform Committee, on "Welfare," July 6, 1960.
    Tab 41 NAR Statement -- excerpt from transcript of session with Governor Rockefeller and Republican National Platform Committee, on comparison of proposed New York State and Federal health programs, July 19, 1960.
    Tab 42 NAR Statement -- on establishment of statewide system to assemble information on hospitals and related facilities, October 20, 1960.
    Tab 43 NAR Statement -- on meeting conducted to discuss medical care problems resulting from American Medical Association decision concerning foreign physicians, December 29, 1960.
    Tab 44 Report -- Special Task Force to Study Catastrophic Expense Health Insurance, December 1960 (Release January 27, 1961).
  - Volume 17 - Health, Mental Health, and Narcotics Addiction, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 167)
    Tab 46 NAR Statement -- Announcement of establishment of four centers for training of non-certified foreign medical graduates, January 15, 1961.
    Tab 47 NAR Statement -- telecast by Governor Rockefeller, Senate Majority Leader and Commissioner of Health, on State's program of medical assistance for the aged, New York City, January 18, 1961.
    Tab 48 NAR Statement -- Announcement of accelerated construction of West Seneca School for the Mentally retarded, February 7, 1961.
    Tab 49 NAR Statement -- Announcement of proposed $18-20 million State University Teaching Hospital of the Upstate Medical Center at Syracuse, April 13, 1961.
    Tab 50 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 237, Pr. 237, authorizing the licensing of bioanalysists, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 51 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bills, Int. 3574, Int. 3479, Int. 3573, Int. 3480, increasing the continuation of health insurance coverage under group policies for retired employees, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 52 Press Release, April 25, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 4849, Pr. 4427, permitting non-profit health insurance corporations to use surplus funds for hospital facilities, April 24, 1961.
    Tab 53 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1961 -- Chapters 281, 95, 46, 157, 429, 792, 773, 203.
    Tab 54 NAR Statement -- Executive Order and announcement by Governor Rockefeller on establishing the Advisory Council on Alcoholism in the Department of Mental Hygiene, June 19, 1961.
    Tab 55 Report -- Interim Report of and statement on Governor's Council on Rehabilitation, July 3, 1961.
    Tab 56 NAR Statement -- Announcement of appointments to State Hospital Review and Planning Council, July 10, 1961
    Tab 57 NAR Statement -- Announcement of conversion of Fairmount Division of Syracuse State School, for the treatment of emotionally disturbed children, July 18, 1961.
    Tab 58 NAR Statement -- Address to Union Label and Service Trades Council of Greater New York and Long Island, AFL-CIO, on medical care program for aged, New York City, September 23, 1961.
    Tab 59 NAR Statement -- Announcement at dedication of New York State School for Blind, of five-year pilot project for emotionally disturbed blind children, Batavia, September 23, 1961.
    Tab 60 NAR Statement -- Announcement of $17 million construction program for mentally retarded at Mt. McGregor, October 20, 1961.
    Tab 61 NAR Statement -- Proclamation Muscular Dystrophy Month, October 30, 1961.
    Tab 62 NAR Statement -- Announcement of million-dollar reconstruction project at Willard State hospital, November 7, 1961.
    Tab 63 NAR Statement -- Announcement by NAR and Board of Regents of Special Committee on Special Education to formulate a plan to meet a shortage of qualified medical personnel, December 4, 1961.
    Tab 64 NAR Statement -- Announcement of 20-bed unit for treatment of Narcotic addicts at Utica State Hospital, December 11, 1961.
    Tab 65 NAR Statement -- Letter to Senator Brydges on progress of Joint Legislative Committee on Mental Retardation and Physical Handicap, December 15, 1961.
    Tab 66 NAR Statement -- Announcement of appointment of 12 members to Advisory Council on Alcoholism, December 30, 1961.
    Tab 67 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 3, 1962.
    Tab 68 NAR Statement -- Announcement of introduction of legislation for accelerated attach on narcotics addiction, January 22, 1962.
    Tab 69 NAR Statement -- Letter to President Kennedy requesting removal of bar on wiretape evidence and location of federal narcotics hospital in New York City, to cope with State narcotics problem, March 27, 1962.
    Tab 70 NAR Statement -- on proposed study of chiropractic licensor problem, March 29, 1962.
    Tab 71 Report -- Medical Assistance for the Aged during 1961, March 1962.
    Tab 72 Press Release, April 30, 1962 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 1602, Pr. 3384, exempting a physician from liability in rendering emergency medical treatment, April 30, 1962.
    Tab 73 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1962 -- Chapters 879, 434, 994, 138, 125, 468, 475, 849, 252, 470, 669, 882, 350, 204, 113, Senate Resolution 117.
    Tab 74 NAR Statement -- Address at Statewide Conference on Aging, on Medical Care for the Aged, New York City, May 1, 1962.
    Tab 75 NAR Statement -- Telegram to President Kennedy urging consideration of The Lindsay Bill for Health Care for the Aged, May 1, 1962.
    Tab 76 NAR Statement -- Address at annual Conference of New York State Public Health Association, on the administration's 3 1/2 years progress in improving the health of New York residents, Syracuse, June 12, 1962.
    Tab 77 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address at Pilgrim State Hospital, on Governor's experiences in community mental health programs, July 17, 1962.
    Tab 78 NAR Statement -- on appointment of members to the Council on Drug Addiction, September4, 1962.
  - Volume 18 - Housing and Rent Control, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 168)
    Tab 1 NAR Campaign Statement -- Policy statement on Housing, October 13, 1958.
    Tab 2 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpt from statement on campaign proposals, October 19, 1958.
    Tab 3 NAR Campaign Statement -- excerpts from remarks delivered at Puerto Rican Block Party, New York, October 24, 1958.
    Tab 4 NAR Campaign Statement -- during campaign on Governor Harriman and housing, October 25, 1958.
    Tab 5 NAR Campaign Statement -- on rent control, October 30, 1958.
    Tab 6 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 7, 1959.
    Tab 7 NAR Statement -- on Middle Income Housing, January 26, 1959.
    Tab 8 NAR Statement -- Special Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, February 9, 1959.
    Tab 9 NAR Statement -- Special Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, February 16, 1959.
    Tab 10 Legislation -- An Act, To amend the general municipal law, the local finance and the state finance law to provide state loans and subsidies for urban renewal programs, February 17, 1959.
    Tab 11 Legislation -- An Act, To amend the public housing law, and the personal property law, in relation to the making of loans to limited-profit housing companies, the establishment of the limited-profit housing mortgage corporation, the voluntary dissolution or sale of limited-profit housing company projects, and the investment of funds in limited-profit housing company obligations, March 17, 1959.
    Tab 12 NAR Statement -- Special Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature on Housing, March 18, 1959.
    Tab 13 Legislation -- An Act, To amend the emergency housing rent control law, generally, March 19, 1959.
    Tab 14 NAR Statement -- text of Statewide telecast by Governor Rockefeller over WRCA-TV, April 8, 1959.
    Tab 15 Report -- Task Force on Middle-Income Housing (interim report), March 9, 1959.
  - Volume 18 - Housing and Rent Control, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 169)
    Tab 16 Report -- Task Force on Middle-Income Housing (Second and Final Report, Interim Report), May 27, 1959.
    Tab 17 NAR Statement -- commenting on the Task force Report on Middle-Income Housing, June 6, 1959.
    Tab 18 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Chapters 695, 808-811, 601, 675, 722, 198.
    Tab 19 NAR Statement -- Address to New York State Association of Real Estate Boards, Lake George, on Middle-Income Housing Program, June 5, 1959.
    Tab 20 NAR Statement -- appointing Temporary Board of Director for the Limited-Profit Housing Mortgage Corporation, August 10, 1959.
    Tab 21 NAR Statement -- Address to Mortgage Bankers Association of America, September 21, 1959.
    Tab 22 Summary of Special Study on Middle-Income Housing -- Legislative Research Report, November 11, 1959.
    Tab 23 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 6, 1960.
    Tab 24 NAR Statement -- Announcement of largest cooperative housing project in country, February 16, 1960.
    Tab 25 NAR Statement -- Special Message to the Legislature on Middle-Income Housing, February 22, 1960.
    Tab 26 NAR Statement -- transcript of statewide telecast by NAR and Commissioner of Housing, on Middle-Income Housing, March 2, 1960.
    Tab 27 NAR Statement -- Special Message to the Legislature on Civil Rights in housing and commercial space, March 31, 1960.
    Tab 28 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1960 -- Chapters 671, 174, 357, 730, 959, 433, 434.
    Tab 29 NAR Statement -- on appointment of New York State Housing Finance Agency, September 13, 1960.
  - Volume 18 - Housing and Rent Control, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 170)
    Tab 30 NAR Statement -- on appointment of Special Committee to Evaluate Effects of Emergency Housing Rent Control Law, November 4, 1960.
    Tab 31 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 4, 1961.
    Tab 32 NAR Statement -- expressing gratification of Senators to support civil rights in private dwellings, February 7, 1961.
    Tab 33 Report -- Special Committee on Rent Control, February 20, 1961.
    Tab 34 NAR Statement -- announcing availability of $50 million in loan funds and tax exemptions for housing for aging citizens, and establishment of Office on Housing for the Aging, March 29, 1961.
    Tab 35 Press Release, April 6, 1961 -- Veto memorandum by Governor Rockefeller on Assembly Bill Int. 3487, Pr. 3487, Pr. 3617 (Sponsored by Mayor Wagner), relieving New York City from supervising the construction of housing projects, April 3, 1961.
    Tab 36 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Bill, Int. 3109, Pr. 4551, permitting low-interest mortgage loans by municipalities for rehabilitation of multiple dwellings, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 37 Press Release, April 24, 1961 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Bill, Int. 4442, Pr. 4707, preventing the removal of an "undesirable" tenant from public housing unless so established in a court proceeding, April 22, 1961.
    Tab 38 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1961 -- Chapters 432, 376, 503, 803, 804, 544, 547, 756, 748, 337, 332.
    Tab 39 NAR Statement -- excerpts from telecast on WCBS-TV, on Review of 1961 Legislative Session, concerning housing and rent control legislation, April 26, 1961.
    Tab 40 NAR Statement -- Address at ground breaking ceremonies for largest housing cooperative in the nation, Rockdale Village, April 29, 1961.
    Tab 41 NAR Statement -- excerpt from meeting of Governor Rockefeller with Community leaders of Queens, Nassau and Bronx, on lack of adequate housing as cause for segregation, August 1, 1961.
    Tab 42 NAR Statement -- excerpt from address to Annual American Municipal Congress, on New York State housing program, Seattle, August 28, 1961.
    Tab 43 NAR Statement -- on NAR participation in ceremonies inaugurating three middle-income housing projects in Rochester, September 13, 1961.
    Tab 44 Report -- Study Committee for Urban Middle Income Housing, October 19, 1961.
    Tab 45 NAR Statement -- announcing 10-year housing program for one million persons in New York City, October 19, 1961.
    Tab 46 NAR Statement -- answering Mayor Wagner's charges on rent control, October 29, 1961.
    Tab 47 NAR Statement -- excerpt from TV interview by Tom Costigan, on Rent Control in New York City, November 9, 1961.
    Tab 48 NAR Statement -- letter to Mayor Wagner concerning State's program of housing and rent control for New York City, December 14, 1961.
    Tab 49 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 3, 1962.
    Tab 50 NAR Statement -- Announcement of proposed legislation to turn over rent control in New York City to the City government, January 22, 1962.
    Tab 51 NAR Statement -- letter to Mayor Wagner, on signing legislation to turn over rent control to New York City, February 18, 1962.
    Tab 52 NAR Statement -- Announcement of proposed construction of two State-aided low-rent housing projects in Little Falls, February 23, 1962.
    Tab 53 NAR Statement -- Address to representatives of NAACP on HOPE and LIFE housing programs and steps to eliminate discrimination in housing, Albany, March 6, 1962.
    Tab 54 NAR Statement -- letter to Senator Mitchell, supporting the "Receivership Bill" to combat slums in multiple dwellings, March 7, 1962.
    Tab 55 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1962 -- Chapters 855-859, 716, 828, 829, 835, 489, 814, 815, 817, 904, 492, 997, 170, 21, 126, 777, 973, 720, 721, Assembly Bill, Int. 4917.
    Tab 56 NAR Statement -- excerpts from address by Governor Rockefeller at 10th Annual Republican Women's Conference, on New York's program on housing, Washington, D.C., April 17, 1962.
    Tab 57 NAR Statement -- urging Mayor Wagner to turn over all evidence of alleged wrong doing in rent control administration, July 31, 1962.
  - Volume 19 - Judiciary, the Courts, and the Laws, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 171)
    Tab 1 Summary and Background on the Judiciary and the Courts in New York -- prepared principally by Carroll L. Wainwright for NAR Special New York Project (Perkins-Kieffer), May 27, 1958.
    Tab 2 Fact Sheet -- "Court Reorganization," prepared by Republican Legislative Research Staff, 1958.
    Tab 3 NAR Statement -- excerpt from "Right Now!", telecast presented in association with The League of Women Voters over WCBS-TV, October 25, 1958.
    Tab 4 NAR Statement -- statement of NAR, Walter Mahoney, Oswald D. Heck, and Joseph C. Carlino on reorganization.
    Tab 5 NAR Statement -- excerpt from Annual Message of Governor Rockefeller to the Legislature, January 7, 1959.
    Tab 6 Legislation -- Resolution of the Senate and Assembly: Proposing a new article six of the constitution, in relation to establishment of a simplified statewide court system, and repeal of the article six of the constitution presently in force, January 28, 1959.
    Tab 7 NAR Statement -- on vote of the Legislature on court reorganization, March 24, 1959.
    Tab 8 Summary: Major Legislative Accomplishments, 1959 -- Senate Pr. 4319 and Chapter 202.
    Tab 9 Press Release, April 24, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Assembly Int. 787, Pr. 1699, requiring notice to attorneys by administrative bodies, April 22, 1959.
    Tab 10 Press Release, April 25, 1959 -- Veto memorandum on Senate Int. 2569, Pr. 2676, authorizing compensation to assigned counsel, April 23, 1959.
  - Volume 19 - Judiciary, the Courts, and the Laws, 1958-1962 (Box 30, Folder 172)
    Tab 11 NAR Statement -- Address at opening of Court of Appeals building, Albany, October 5, 1959.
    Tab 12 Report -- Temporary Commission on the Revision and Simplification of the Constitution, December 31, 1959.